<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A general epistle to all Friends.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 22KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B23124</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888317</idno>
  <idno type="VID">193474</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240887094</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1824</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 1478.aa.24[25]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R229324</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888317</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888317e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B23124)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 193474)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; B8:2[25])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A general epistle to all Friends.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[1], 7+ p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for M.W.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1664]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed on p. 7: G.F. [i.e. George Fox].</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>First line of text: All my dear Freinds [sic], and brethren who are of the royal seed.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: lacking all after p. 7. Catchword on p. 7 "And".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  Pastoral letters and charges --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Christian life --  Quaker authors --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="tract">
            <pb facs="tcp:193474:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:193474:1"/>
            <head>A General Epistle to all Friends.</head>
            <p>ALL my dear Freinds, and Brethren who are of the Royal Seed of God, patience obtaine the victory that runs the race, and obtaines the Crown, and be married and joyned to the Seed Christ the Lamb slaine from the Foundation of the World, from its foundation I say; Therefore as you are joyned to the Seed and married to that which hath been slain from the foundation of the world which hath the victory, and doth overcome; by which you come to the end of the world, marke to its end. And now all freinds look upon the sufferings that hath been since the Fall and since the world began. And again look upon the Valiant Prisoners and such as stood with the Lord and for the Lord; and followed, and obeyed his movings, and motions, and Commands with victories they had; how they tryumphed in the Lord over that which was against the Lord, for by Faith <hi>Abraham</hi> forsook his Country, and his Fathers house, and his national worship. And by Faith was <hi>Abels</hi> Offering accepted of God, unto whom God had respect; Therefore did wicked <hi>Cain</hi> persecute, and kill him about his Religion, and this was not long after man was fallen from the righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ousness and the power, and the Image of God which man was made in. And by the Faith, and the power and wisdome of God did <hi>Moses</hi> goe down and speak to <hi>Pharaoh</hi> the King of <hi>Egypt,</hi> and through the power and Hand and Arme of God lead them out of <hi>Egypt,</hi> which signifies mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sery, Thraldom, and Bondage thereby, afterwards when they were come out, and had tasted the power of God, many fell. And <hi>Moses</hi> saw Christ the great Prophet that was to come, which was to build his House (as <hi>Moses</hi> by the wisdome of God had done his in the time of the Law, with Types, Figures, and Shadows) and so look upon <hi>Moses</hi> how he Conquered all the Magicians, and comprehended all the Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerers; and Southsayers, and <hi>Pharachs</hi> Religion and their worship; and could not bow nor bend unto it.</p>
            <p>Look upon <hi>Ioseph</hi> who through the emnity in his Brethern was sould into <hi>Egypty</hi> who underwent reproach and imprisonment; unto whom God gave power over all at last, and confounded all the Wise men and
<pb n="1" facs="tcp:193474:2"/>the national Worshippers in <hi>Egypt,</hi> and came in favour over them all by the power of God: And remember <hi>Abraham</hi> who was in the Faith and the fear of God, and how <hi>Abimalths</hi> house for his sake God plagued. Therefore keep in the faith of <hi>Abraham;</hi> then who wrongs you the hand of the Lord will turne against them, and whilest they stood in the power of God what victories they had over their Enemies, as instance <hi>Samson, David,</hi> and <hi>Saul;</hi> But when any went from the command of God, how under the Heathen they fell. So now ye who are come to Gods power, which goes over the power of darkness, and before it was; in that stand, tryumph, and trample who are come to the end of carnal. weapons and striving with outward Armes; And ye may look upon them how valliant they were over the <hi>Philistines</hi> both <hi>Samson</hi> and <hi>David,</hi> and his mighty men when they were in the power of God, and how <hi>Davids</hi> three mighty men, broke through a whole Host to fetch water to refresh the Seed <hi>(David:)</hi> Therefore now ye in the power of the Lord (and the mighty God) which goes over all the <hi>Philistines</hi> of the Earth with Carnal weapons as there they in the time of the Law did with Carnal weapons. And how often <hi>Iacobs</hi> Well was stopped up (the beloved of God the second birth,) by the <hi>Philistines,</hi> but <hi>Iacob</hi> did thresh the Mountains, as he did arise, and drove them away by which he might drink again. So read this in the substance who are come to the second birth, that goes over <hi>Esau</hi> and the <hi>Philistines</hi> both before they were; And al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so remember how the Prophets were Imprisoned, and put in Dungeons, and Stocks, &amp;c. As in particular <hi>Ieremiah,</hi> and how they were mocked, and scoffed at, and reproached for declaring against the fins, and wickedness of the times, both by Rulers, Teachers, and people; and yet by the power of God they were carried through, and over all: and the Cry was then Cursed is he that puts his trust in man, or feared man, or the Arme of Flesh, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>So remember <hi>Daniel,</hi> and the three Children though Prisoners, yet could not bow to the National worship, and so were cast into the firy Furnace, and the Den of Lyons, whom the Lord God gave Dominion over their Enemies, and confounded the National worshippers, with all the Magicians, and made the King to change his Decree, and Law; and this was in the Babylonish Monarchy; and when the <hi>Medes</hi> and <hi>Persians</hi> got up, the power was changed, then they cast <hi>Daniel</hi> into the Den of Lyons because he prayed to his God contrary to the Kings De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree, to whom God appeared again and confounded them all, and made
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:193474:2"/>the King or Emperour to change his Decree: Therefore to keep faith in the power of God; for that is it by which the Elders of old obteined a good report; And consider <hi>Mordecay</hi> who stood faithful and could not bow to proud flesh though it was in danger of destroying all the <hi>Iews,</hi> whom through obedience to God he gave him victory by which he came to answer the good in all people. Now consider they that came to profess Christ who was the Substance before the Types, figures, and shadows which were held up by the <hi>Iews</hi> in the Law and first Covenant and Preisthood and Ordinances (which Christ the Substance came to end) how that I say the Christians of old by that kinde of people the <hi>Iews</hi> as you do now suffer the most, and have done by them that are the greatest professors of Christs words, but out of the life and power of Christ, and the Apostles and Saints were in, in the Primitive times.</p>
            <p>So it is no new thing, and as <hi>Solomon</hi> saith here is no new thing un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Sun, for it is not a new thing for the birth that is born after the flesh to persecute the Birth that is born after the Spirit; And look upon the Apostles and consider how they suffered (and by whom) that bore testimony to the Substance, their sufferings were by such as were in the husks, shadows, inventions, and rudiments of the world, and such as were fallen from Gods righteousness, Image and holiness, and not in the renewed State. And consider how that the <hi>Hebrews</hi> suffered the spoyling of their goods by the <hi>Hebrews</hi> who were called <hi>Iews,</hi> as ye may read it in the Epistle to the <hi>Hebrews,</hi> for ye read in few of the Epistles that the <hi>Gentiles</hi> suffered the spoyling of their goods (or the <hi>Christians</hi> by the <hi>Gentiles,</hi>) but by the <hi>Iews</hi> the great professors as you do and have done in these days.</p>
            <p>And consider how the Witness hath been slain and (the true Church) the woman went into the Wilderness, sled, who was persecuted, and how she hath been fed there of God, and how since that time the Beast and Dragons worship hath been up and the false Prophet, and the Whore (the false Church) which hath Riden on the Beast in the Dragons power whom the people have worshipped; who hath caused all Nations to drink of the Whores Cup of Fornication; Now you that have appeared in the end and behinde all the Worships of the Beast, and after the Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship of the Dragon, who comes now to fathom the Whore (the false Church) and the false Prophets, and comes to see the power, and to feel it, and to be in it that takes them and cast them alive into the Lake of fire (which hath been worshiped) and burns the Whores flesh with
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:193474:3"/>fire, which power gives them Dominion over them all to see to the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Apostles days what they were in and what hath got up since, for it is above sixteen hundred years since the false Prophets, and Antichrists came in (therefore they may plead Antiquity,) Now with the power of God, ye may look what raikes they have playd in the world since the primative times in the Apostacy: But now is the Bride coming up out of the Wilderness, and the Prophet is risen and arising that the everlast<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Gospel shall be, and is preached again to all Nations, Kindreds, Tongues, and peoples, and they that dwell upon the Earth; and the Reapers are going forth to reap people down and up to God, and bring them into the Barne, and to gather the Wheat into the Gamer. And people shall come to worship God that made Heaven and Earth, the Sea and all that is therein; the Beasts Worship is falling, and Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gons Worship, and the great Whores Church is falling (the true woman is coming up) false Prephets are falling, true Prophets and true Witnes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses rising, and risen; Sing tryumph and rejoyce glory in the highest, trample, tread, and bow before the mighty God: Let the wicked bow before the gates of the Righteous, sing and rejoyce, the Heaven of Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens praise the Lord. Now as the Dragons Worship, Beast, false Church, false Prophet is taken, the old Dragon cast into the Lake of fire, (and with him the false Prophets) and the flesh of the Whore burnt, Reap out, reap out, reap out I say (with the power of God) ye Reapers unto the Lord, for here is the day of Harvest, for as the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther falls the day of Harvest is known, a day of gathering, for it is that which hath inwardly ravened, that hath scattered. For the inwardly ravenors, the Wolves in Sheeps cloathing, whose fruits have been Bryers &amp; Thorns and Thistles, are them which have made up the false Church, the Whore, the false Prophets, and the Beasts worship, and the Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gons worship out of the truth, which have made the world like a Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derness, overgrown with Thistles, Thorns, and Bryars, in which lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the Wolves and Dragons, which the beginning of this ravening into this state was a matter of sixteen hundred years since, amongst whom is found the blood of the Martyers, Prophets, and Saints in the faith, and in the Testimony of Jesus; in this dark night of Apostacy, sepera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion degeneration, with all their compelling Worships, inventions, Laws, Traditions, Churches rudiments to be observed, and Cups for people to drink; in these (I say) and amongst these have the Righteous suffered since the days of the Apostles: and amongst them is the blood of
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:193474:3"/>the Martyrs, and the Prophets, and holy people of the Royal seed found, and by them have they all suffered, and from amongst them will God fetch his Royal seed with his own hand, and with his mighty power will he fetch it; Glory over all, to him rejoyce and sing praises, who is now tryumphing gloriously, and bringing ye over with his power, that ye might see to the beginning before man fell, and know the state of the <hi>Iews</hi> in the Law, and the state of the <hi>Christians</hi> in the end of the Law, and the state of the Apostatized pretended <hi>Christians</hi> since the Apostles days out of both Law and Gospel, how they have gotten up and in what they have lived out of the life, and power the Apostles were in, and Christ Jesus who is the first, and the last, the top, and Corner stone who is over all felt, and lyes heavy upon the Transgressors, who is the Rock upon which the Lambs, leaps, and skips; him all feel in you all then ye may all feel the first and the last, who destroys the Devil and his works (which are imperfect) whose works are Persecution and Murder, and Banishment, and Cruelty, and Imprisonment: For the Devil shall cast some into Prison saith <hi>Iohn</hi> in the <hi>Revellations,</hi> and the Devil was a murderer from the beginning, and a Lyer, whom Christ de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroys, and his works who was before he was, and remaines when he is destroyed and gone, and his works.</p>
            <p>Therefore in him (the seed) have ye life eternal, and in him meet together, and then ye are in the Pastures of life, who is the first and the last, who is over Death and the power of it, and the Pastures of Death; So who be in this Royal seed comprehends the state and time before the Law, the time of the Law, the time of <hi>Christians,</hi> and the time of the Apostacy; for the seed Christ is the first and the last, the beginning &amp; the ending, and in the seed is the staydness, and the plainness of words and life, (yet a mistery to all them that be out of it.) And comprehends and sees the state of the sufferings before the Law of the just, the state of the sufferings of the just in the Law, by whom and for what they suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fred, and also comprehends the state of the <hi>Christians</hi> who lived in the end of the Law, in Christ the substance, and by whom they suffered and for what; even by such as were the greatest Professors, out of the life of <hi>Moses</hi> and the Prophets, which had they been in it they would have read Christ the Substance, and all them that testified of him, and were witnesses of him. And also comprehends the state and sees who are them that are Apostatized from the Apostles and the Church in the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:193474:4"/>Primative times, who have been the sufferers, and who it is that hath made them to suffer, and for what.</p>
            <p>So the measuring Line of Righteousness is in this known, and also the state now wherein the Lambs and the Saints shall have the victory; and the rising of the witnesses, and the Prophets, and the Reapers go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forth to reap the earth, and the womans coming out of the Wilder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, and the worshiping of God that made Heaven and Earth, the Sea and the dry Land; and the destruction of the Devils worship, and Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gons, and the false Prophets, and the great Whore (the false Church) and the Saints shall Raign, and the Lambs shall have victory, and the Kid the Lambs wife shall be known, (which is the true Church which Christ is the head of,) So in this live that is in the life and power of Christ in Christ the Substance in which ye may know the first &amp; the last, and the Gospel fellowship which is preached again, which Gospel is the power of God which brings before the power of darkness was, which hath darkned life and immortallity from people in which power, life, and immortallity comes to be brought to light again to people in which power of God is the fellowship, which is a mistery. So wait to know every particular of your selves, to be heires of this, and know your por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, the power of God, the Gospel fellowship, then are ye Members one of another, and living stones that build up the Spiritual houshould; And also know the Cross of Christ, which is the power of God, which Crucifies from the state in the fall, and the Apostacy from that state, I say that <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> and all their Sons and Daughters are in, in the fall wherein that state they glory in the Creatures, and in their shame, and in their Inventions, or in their Strength, Wisdome, Riches. But the glorying in the Cross of Christ the power of God, the glorying is in that which doth Crucifie from the state of <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve,</hi> and all their Sons and daughters in the fall, and from that state all the Apostate Christians be in since the Apostles; and in this power of God is everlast<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing gloryings, which is a Cross to all that lives as I said before, in the Apostacy, and in the fall, but not a Cross to them that be redeemed, and Crucified, for their glorying stands in it which is over all the glory<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings in the fall, and all Creatures. So in the power of the Lord God, meet, waite, live, and dwell, and have fellowship, for in the power Christ lives: Therefore now you that are come to know the Gospel preached again which was amongst the Apostles, in which power of God you feel before the fall of <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve,</hi> where all things were
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:193474:4"/>good and blest in the beginning before the fall; which after the fall, the Curse came which brought the woe and misery: So you that feel the Redemption out of the fall, by which you know the state of the bles<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing before the fall, how all things were good and blessed, and come into the same power that brings you up before the fall, and brings you to be gathered in the Name of Jesus, which is above every Name, and gathered into the Name of Jesus, by which Salvation is brought, and there is no other name under Heaven given by which Salvation is brought but by the Name of Jesus. So ye being gathered in the Name which is above every name, and also into the Name by which Salvation is brought, and by no other name; in that waite, and meet, and keep together, so ye will feel the blessing of the Lord in you, and amongst you so farwel.</p>
            <p>And consider how the Servants of the Lord, and his Royal people, and Prophets, feared not flames, feared not Dens of Lyons, or Dragons, heeded not Prisonments, Bonds, Banishments, whips nor Scourgings, nor spoyling of their goods, and their tortures, nor feared not their Saws of being sawed asunder, nor their Stocks, their Clubs and Staves, nor Persecution; but chose rather to suffer reproach with the people of God, then to enjoy the pleasures of Sin for a season: and how that re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proaches, slanders, vilfiing words they regarded not, but trampled up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on such, and said the sufferings were not to be vallued with the Excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lency and riches of grace, which they were made partakers of. And the cry was what shall seperate us from the Love of God, which we have in Christ Jesus, shall Death, shall Famine, or Sword, or Persecution, or Cold, or Nakedness, or Things present, or Things to come, or Heigth, or Depth, or Angels, or Men, or Principallities, or Powers seperate us from the Love of God &amp;c. For by the powers were all the National Worships held up as they are at this day, which the false Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets, the Teachers, and the powers joyned together then against them that were in the Faith, by which faith they overcame, and said there was not any thing that was able to seperate them from the Love of God which they had in Christ Jesus, marke Christ the seed who de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroys the Devil and his works; in which seed (Christ) ye come over the Devil the Author of all Prisoning, Persecuting, Darkness, Ungod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liness, Unrighteousness, Unholiness; Christ who doth subdue all things to himself, whose Kingdome is an everlasting Kingdome, and Domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion, an everlasting Dominion over all Dominions: And in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:193474:5"/>and Dominion have ye all peace where no unrighteous thing enters: And so in this ye come to be a free people in life, and power, and Dominion; And there is no new thing under the Sun, for the wicked cryes, light is darkness yet (as of old time,) and calls good evil, and evil good, and truth errour, and cryes up the false Teachers, and Prophets, for the true and false Church and worship, and the feigned humility for the true, and the blind zeal for the good, and true zeal, now as in former days, and so it is the old Enemy of mankinde, and his works which the seed destroys, who Raignes Glory for ever to the Highest.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="tract">
            <p>FRIENDS, <hi>all outward things figures, Types, Shadowes, and inven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions have been set up since</hi> Adam <hi>fell, which invention Christ destroies, and the Types, Figures and shadowes of him fulfils, and brings man up out of the fall to the state he was in before he fell, and so in the power of God in peace, love, and unity, and into the everlasting fellowship.</hi> Cain <hi>differed from</hi> Abel <hi>in matter of worship,</hi> Abraham <hi>from his own Countrymen and Nation: Likewise in matters of worship,</hi> Moses <hi>and the children differed from the Egyptians, and the</hi> Canaanites <hi>and other nations in matter of wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship. Yet after the children of Israel were brought out of</hi> Egypt <hi>by the pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of God, how soon after did they set up a calf an outward thing? There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore in the power of God keep over all things, and in his wisdome: And how soon</hi> Chora, Dathan <hi>and</hi> Abyram <hi>began to offer a strange sacrifice, after they were brought out of</hi> Egypt <hi>by the power of God; and went from the power of God, in which they should have offered, therefore in the power of God keep.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And how soon the children of</hi> Israel <hi>(when they multiplyed and grew un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merous) offered out of the life of the Law, and the power of God, then their Sacrifices were like unto the cutting off of a doggs neck, and blessing Idols, therfore keep in the life and power of God. And ye may see</hi> Daniels <hi>Religion and worship differed from</hi> Nebuchadnessars <hi>the Emperour of</hi> Babylon, <hi>and likewise differed from the</hi> Caldeans <hi>and</hi> Persians <hi>as yours comes to differ now from all the Apostates from the Apostles, and Christs life and doctrine, and there is the mistery of</hi> Babylon, <hi>as the Iews differed from outward</hi> Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bylon, <hi>therefore keep in the power of God, that keeps you to the beginning.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:193474:5"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>